Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-yahya-butt-533ab3155 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Technical Support
Transaction Processing
ATM Configuration

Muhammad Yahya Butt

Application Consultant at Euronet Pakistan (Private) Limited Pakistan

Summary

Experienced in 'OPERATION AND CUSTOMER SUPPORT' in Banking/ Card / Payment scheme. Responsible for daily processes includes (clearing, settlement of incoming and outgoing, reconciliation and backend support in financial operations). Skilled to provide level 1 and level 2 support to customer (Member Banks) facing issues which includes (system issues, financial/non-financial transaction issues in ATM and POS acquiring, configuration level issues, EFT, IBFT, card management system issues). Also provide highly complex technical support to customers by resolving system and office related matters.

Responsibility to submit the Visa Outgoing.

Experience

Euronet Pakistan 2 years 10 months

Application Consultant February 2022 - Present (2 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Technical Support Analyst April 2021 - February 2022 (11 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

- Acquirer / ATMs / POS / Channels configuration into system.
- Issuer configurations into system as well as connection with CBS for Debit accounts authorizations.
- Providing Technical Level Support for Alternate Distributed Channels Transactions.
- Capturing issues in system before identified by clients.
- Resolving basic reported issues as BAU.
- Perform root cause analysis for resolution of issue.
- Resolution of any issue occurred in Card Generation Process.
- Resolution of issues occurred during settlement/processes.
- HSM Support for Keys Generation & Migration via Console Mode.

- Highlights issues in system to international Support for resolution.
- Co-ordination with Payment Gateways support teams for raised cases.
- Discussion with Vendors & Customers to bring cases towards solution.
- Participating in Mandates testing and implementation in production environment.
- Co-ordination with development team for new process and products.
- Perform Descriptive Quality Assurance Testing before UAT.
- Support customers [Banks] for User Acceptance Tests.
- Implementation of projects into the production environment.
- Customer [Banks] Query Responses.

Associate System Engineer

June 2019 - April 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Pakistan

- Worked as a core member of Operations helping management in building the initial 24x7 Team.
- First point of contact for customer in need of support.
- Execution of End of Day processes and analyzing in depth to smooth the execution on daily basis.
- Creation of SOP for each of the tasks and daily updating the same.
- Logging Calls & generation of Tickets.
- Alternate Distributed Channels Transaction Monitoring and working with external teams to resolve issues on spot.
- Responsible to keep the transactions flow uninterrupted.
- Execution of Card Handoff File for Card Generation.
- Network Monitoring and identify issues with immediate reporting to relevant teams.
- Address to customer Queries and provide appropriate responses.
- Perform initial investigation before raising it further within TAT keeping the regular tasks uninterrupted.
- Raise Issues to Technical Supports & Follow up for timely resolution under SLA.
- Acquiring & Gateways; Modules & Nodes Monitoring.
- Systems Scheduled Backup Processing and record keeping of Backups for recovery.
- Disaster Recovery health check and availability tests.
- · Maintaining 24x7 Task Sheets.

CubeXS Weatherly (Pvt) Ltd.
Technical Support Engineer
February 2019 - May 2019 (4 months)

Karachi, Pakistan

- Advised senior personnel on potential process improvements to increase support quality and expedite ticket fulfillment.
- Performed root cause analysis of reported issues to decisively discern and enact corrections.

Education

Iqra University (Official)

Master's degree, Computer Science · (January 2020 - May 2022)

Iqra University (Official)
Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Sciences · (2014 - 2018)